to see what raid 0 reliability looks
like let's assume
that f is a failure rate for a single
disk
a failure rate is really how many
failures do we expect for a single
working disk to have in a second
obviously this number will be extremely
small
usually we can assume that the failure
rate is constant over time that is every
second if the disk is working at the
beginning of the second it has the same
failure rate during that second
for a single disk then
the mttf the mean time to failure will
be
one over f
so for example if the disk has one
millionth of a failure per second then
the mttf will be
1 million seconds
for disks the mttf is also sometimes
called
mean time to data loss or how long until
we lose some data on this disk
and for a single disk the mean time to
data loss is the same as the mttf of one
disk
now let's look at what happens when we
have
and such disks in a raid 0 configuration
it turns out that the failure rate when
we have n working disks
is equal to n times
the failure rate
of one disk
this is because for example if we can
expect one millionth of a failure per
working disk per second
then we can expect one failure per
million working disks per second so if
we start the second with a million
working disks
chances are that one of them will fail
during the second if we start the second
with half a million working disks
on average half of a single disk will
fail per second and so on
it also turns out that the mean time to
the first failure among n working disks
has the same distribution as the first
failure for the single disk
so we get that mttf
for n disks
in a raid zero configuration where mttf
is really the mean time to data loss in
this case
is equal to
the mttf of one disk
divided by n
so if you have two disks the mttf of the
raid 0 array with two disks will be half
of the fttf of a single disk
a single disk typically will have the
mttf on the order of 10-ish years to
maybe 100 years
so if we have too many disks in a raid
zero configuration we can reduce the
mttf so the average disk will not fail
in the five or six years that we
actually end up using it
but if we have two or three or four such
disks then we can expect the array to
fail at least once until we actually get
rid of it